Hong Bui | Software Engineer

Dallas, TX | (781) 484-7669 | hong.b918@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio - Github

About

I am a first-generation Vietnamese software developer who has skills in both front-end and back-end of web applications. I have a passion for creating aesthetically functional websites and a strong interest in researching and testing for errors. I seek a role as a software developer where I can be driven to create a product that is more inclusive and advanced in social impacts.

Skills

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, EJS, DTL

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Bootstrap

Tools - Visual Studio Code, Heroku, Zoom, Postman, GitHub, Trello, Figma, Excalidraw, Monday

Software Development Projects

January - July 2022

Thue - E-commerce application that allows users to purchase furniture products online

July 2022

- Assembled a full-stack application with Django and React that sends API calls using Redux for managing application state,
 PayPal for payment method, and JWT for user authentication
- Implemented Python functions and methods on server-side to load data from PostGresSQL and create a RESTful API through Django REST Framework
- Wireframed and planned UI design of application using Figma and tracked project progress using Trello
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment on Heroku

Git Master

Every Volt - Application that allows users to find nearby electric vehicle charging stations using Google Maps

June 2022

- Collaborated with a Project Manager and Deploy Daemon to implement a MERN stack application with the team design, built using React, Express, Node.js and MongoDB with full CRUD functionality
- Optimized Git flow by proposing communication strategy and branching model that minimized merge conflicts
- Initiated third-party APIs calls to display Google Maps on frontend with targeted locations from OpenChargeAPI

Professional Experience

Quality Analyst | Goosehead Insurance Agency | Westlake, TX

February 2022 - Current

- Analyzed over 100 business portfolios daily to ensure insurance policies are in accordance to guidelines using Salesforce Lightning
- Advised insurance agents on procedures and errors to help clients prevent financial losses and mitigate risks
- Assembled monthly reports using Salesforce Classic to identify trend of errors in writing insurance policies within different business territory or insurance carriers
- Visualized the correlation in data and results using Power BI and deliver strategies to leaders to reduce risk exposures

Mortgage Processor | Caliber Home Loans | Remote

June 2020 - January 2022

- Streamlined the mortgage loan process by compiling loan application documentation and followed up with clients
- Managed multi-state loan pipeline of over 80 files with an advanced level of detail orientation
- Created reports from Tableau and communicate overall progress to key stakeholders, including Branch Manager,
 Management team

Education

General Assembly | Remote

January 2022 - July 2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

University of Massachusetts Amherst | Amherst, MA Bachelor of Science in Psychology; Pre-Med